Guide to the Jones Graduate School of Administration - Council of Overseers records, 1977-1988 UA 278
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Jones Graduate School of Administration - Council of Overseers records
1977-1988
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University.
UA 278
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Records of meetings of the Council of Overseers, Jones Graduate School of Administration, including agendas, table of contents, by-laws and consitutions, minutes, membership lists, financial information, publicity and other material presented at the meetings.
Biographical / Historical
The Jones Graduate School of Business is named after the late Jesse Holman Jones, a world-renowned business and civic leader. Born in Tennessee in 1874, Jones moved to Dallas in 1891, and then to Houston in 1898. He began his business career overseeing lumberyards and sawmills in East Texas and Louisiana, and soon after branched out into construction and banking as he oversaw the construction of some of Houston's tallest buildings in the early twentieth century. During World War I, Jones served as Director of Military Relief for the American Red Cross. Jones was called on for assistance by Presidents Hoover and Roosevelt, and served as chairman of the Rreconstruction Finance Corporation during the Great Depression, overseeing investments in various assistance programs. After serving as Secretary of Commerce during World War II, Jones focused more on his philanthropic efforts, funding various organizations devoted to the arts, environment and human services, as well as museums, scholarships, and student grants, mostly through his philanthropic organization, Houston Endowment, Inc. (excerpted from "Texas Highways," January 2009, p. 5).
The Jesse H. Jones Graduate School of Business received its initial funding in 1974 through a donation from the Houston Endowment. The Jones school offers multiple MBA degrees as well as an undergraduate minor, and its programs have been recognized throughout the world for fostering innovation and leadership. (excerpted from the Jones Graduate School of Business webpage, http://business.rice.edu/About_School.aspx, accessed June 6, 2011)
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of records of meetings of the Council of Overseers, Jones Graduate School of Administration, including agendas, table of contents, by-laws and consitutions, minutes, membership lists, financial information, publicity and other material presented at the meetings.
Access Restrictions
Access to this material is restricted.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Pat Armentor June of 1998.
Index Terms
Subjects
Education, Higher -- Texas; Universities and colleges
Document Types
minutes (administrative records); documents
- Series I: Meetings, 1977-1981, 153598
  - Meeting, 1977-03-04; 153599 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Meeting; Action Committee, 1977-05-11; 153600 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Meeting, 1977-05-19; 153601 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Meeting; Action Committee, 1977-05-27; 153602 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Meeting; Action Committee, 1977-06-10; 153603 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meeting; Action Committee, 1977-06-16; 153604 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Meeting; Action Committee, 1977-07-08; 153605 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Meeting, 1977-07-26; 153606 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Meeting, 1977-09-07; 153607 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Meeting, 1977-09-20; 153608 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Meeting, 1977-11-11; 153609 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Meeting, 1978-02-03; 153610 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Meeting, 1978-04-06; 153611 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Liedtke meeting, 1978-04-25; 153612 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Meeting, 1978-09-08; 153613 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Meeting, 1978-11-02; 153614 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Meeting, 1979-02-01; 153615 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Meeting, 1979-04-05; 153616 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Meeting, 1979-09-26; 153617 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Meeting, 1979-11-01; 153618 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Meeting, 1980-02-07; 153619 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Meeting, 1980-04-17; 153620 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Meeting, 1980-09-05; 153621 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Meeting, 1980-11-07; 153622 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Meeting, 1981-02-12; 153623 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Meeting, 1981-04-02; 153624 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Meeting, 1981-09-03; 153626 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Meeting, 1981-11-05; 153627 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Series II: Meetings, 1982-1988, 153625
  - Meeting, 1981-01-28; 153628 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Meeting, 1982-03-23; 153629 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Meeting, 1982-09-23; 153630 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Information on donations, 1982-10; 153631 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Meeting, 1982-11-04; 153632 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Meeting, 1983-01-27; 153633 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Meeting, 1983-04-29; 153634 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Meeting, 1983-09-22; 153635 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Meeting, 1983-11-03; 153636 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Meeting, 1984-02-02; 153637 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Meeting, 1984-04-05; 153638 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Meeting, 1984-09-06; 153639 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Meeting, 1984-11-02; 153640 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Photos, 1985; 153644 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Meeting, 1985-02-07; 153642 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Meeting, 1985-04-04; 153643 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Meeting, 1985-09-05; 153645 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Meeting, 1985-11-07; 153646 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Meeting, 1986-02-06; 153647 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Meeting, 1986-04-03; 153648 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Meeting, 1987-02-05; 153649 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Meeting, 1987-04-10; 153650 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Membership roster, 1987-09-03; 153651 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Meeting, 1987-10-30; 153652 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Meeting, 1988-02-04; 153653 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Program proposals, 153654 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Membership rosters, 153655 (Box 2, Folder 27)